Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Jack Cronin papers, 1964-1996 and undated RL.11603
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Jack Cronin papers
1964-1996 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11603
21.0 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The London Office first opened in 1899. John J. (Jack) Cronin was an advertising executive who managed JWT's Canadian and European operations before becoming Vice Chairman of JWT. Collection includes correspondence, financial and management statements; research reports; client files and other printed materials along with slides and videocassettes of presentations. Companies represented include various JWT offices as well as Burger King, ComputerLand, Ford, ITV, International Television Association (ITVA), Kellogg, Kraft, Nestle, Pepsi, Philips, Schick and Unilever. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Administration; Clients and Accounts; Correspondence and related materials; Financial; Presentations and speeches; Printed material; and Audiovisual materials
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. It is headquartered in New York. The London Office first opened in 1899. John J. (Jack) Cronin was an advertising executive who managed JWT's Canadian and European operations before becoming Vice Chairman of JWT.
John J. (Jack) Cronin born 1931, Cork, Ireland. Cockfield Brown agency: Copy chief and Creative Director circa 1960. JWT Montreal: Senior copywriter 1964; Creative Director 1966; Senior Vice President and Chief Executive Officer 1977. JWT Canada: Vice President 1967; Director 1972; Chief Operating Officer 1976. JWT Europe: Executive Vice President 1980. JWT corporate: Vice Chairman 1986; Chief Advertising Officer 1987.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, original audiovisual materials are closed until use copies can be produced.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Jack Cronin papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as gifts in 1996 and 2008.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. Account files; J. Walter Thompson Company. Corporate documentation; J. Walter Thompson Company. Frankfurt Office. George Black papers; J. Walter Thompson Company. Harry Clark papers; J. Walter Thompson Company. International advertisements; J. Walter Thompson Company. James Kennedy papers; J. Walter Thompson Company. London Office. Michael Cooper-Evans papers
Collection Overview
Collection includes correspondence, financial and management statements; research reports; client files and other printed materials along with slides and videocassettes of presentations. Materials are in English, French, German, Spanish, Turkish and other languages. Companies represented include various JWT offices as well as Burger King, ComputerLand, Ford, ITV, International Television Association (ITVA), Kellogg, Kraft, Nestle, Pepsi, Philips, Schick and Unilever. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising; Advertising -- Europe; Advertising -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies; Advertising agencies -- Europe; Advertising agencies -- Great Britain; Advertising agencies -- Management; Advertising executives; Advertising executives -- Europe; Advertising executives -- Great Britain; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Burger King Corporation; Ford Motor Company; Eastman Kodak Company; Kellogg Company; Kraft Foods Company; Nestlé; PepsiCo, Inc.; Unilever (Firm)
- Administration, 1973-1990 and undated; 1
  - 1981-1983 marketing plan (Box 1)
  - 1985-1987 marketing plan (Box 1)
  - 1986 planning cycles, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Account planning Europe, 1979-1983; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Acquisition report by Arthur Anderson AG, Zurich, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Administrative reports, 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - Amsterdam--Creative compensation, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Amsterdam--Notes on the three year plan meeting, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Amsterdam--Three year plan meeting, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Annual management assessment and objectives, 1979-1980; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Annual management assessment and objectives, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Appointments, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Athens three year plan 1984-1986, Spot/Thompson (Box 2)
  - Austria acquisition, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Belgium WPP, 1988 (Box 2)
  - Board of Directors meetings, 1980-1986; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Board of Directors meetings multinational target accounts, 1980 (Box 2)
  - Brussels planning materials marketing and three year plan, 1984-1986 (Box 2)
  - Client agency evaluations, 1984-1987; 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Client lists, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Client retention reports, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
  - Client services director meetings, 1985-1986 (Box 3)
  - Copenhagen--Board meeting minutes, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Copenhagen--Three year plan, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Deltakos--Manager's monthly assessments, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Directors' handbook, 1987 (Box 4)
  - EAAA (European Association of Advertising Agencies), 1986; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - EAAA--Annual remuneration survey, 1982-1983 (Box 4)
  - EAAA--Articles of Association, undated (Box 4)
  - EAAA--Balance sheets and profit and loss statements, 1986 (Box 4)
  - EAAA--List of Council members and committees, 1982 (Box 4)
  - EAAA--Minutes of the Council meeting held in athens, 1982 (Box 4)
  - EAAA--President's report to the Council meeting in Helsinki, 1983 (Box 4)
  - EROC (European Regional Operations Committee), 1985 (Box 4)
  - EROC--Bioforce Development Programme, 1985 (Box 4)
  - EROC--Meeting notes, 1982-1986 (Box 4)
  - EROC--Meeting notes, 1982-1986 (Box 5)
  - European employee benefit study, 1983 (Box 5)
  - European monthly management meetings, 1974-1981; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - European operational review, 1983-1985; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Formal reporting requirements to corporate headquarters, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Frankfurt--Administrative correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 6)
  - Frankfurt--Germany facts and figures, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Frankfurt--Marketing plan 1984-1986 (Box 6)
  - Group board meeting, 1985 (Box 6)
  - Hamburg--JWT Direct, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Hamburg--JWT sales promotion: JWT sells, 1988 (Box 6)
  - Hamburg--Strategic alliance in the specialized area of sponsoring (Van Winterfeldt), 1988 (Box 6)
  - International accounts gains-losses report, 1986 (Box 6)
  - JWT Advisory Board system, 1980 (Box 6)
  - London--Annual management assessment and objectives, 1979-1980; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - London--Farm Street office, 1984-1985 (Box 6)
  - London--Group assessment of performance 1979 and objectives for 1980 (Box 6)
  - London--Group three year plan 1980-1983, 1980-1986 (Box 6)
  - London--Marketing plans, 1981-1986; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Management Development Center Troutbeck, 1982-1983; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Management succession review, 1983-1984; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Manager's guide to international transfers, 1984 (Box 7)
  - Manager's handover briefing book, undated (Box 7)
  - Managers' meeting at Schloss Kronberg, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Manchester--Marketing plan 1983-1985 (Box 7)
  - Marketing plans 1983-1984, 1982 (Box 7)
  - Minutes European Managers meetings, 1976-1979; 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Monthly multinational client reports, 1989 (Box 7)
  - MRB Group Limited correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 8)
  - MRB internal audit report, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Multinational client profitability 1986-First quarter annuals (Box 8)
  - Operating policies manual, 1984 (Box 8)
  - Operations Committee meetings, 1983; 10 folders (Box 8)
  - Operations Committee meetings, 1983-1985; 13 folders (Box 9)
  - Operations Committee meetings, 1985-1986; 5 folders (Box 10)
  - Operations planning review, 1980 (Box 10)
  - Operations reviews, 1985; 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Partner Group JWT S.A. multiple employment contract study by Arthur Anderson, undated (Box 11)
  - Partner Group Limited purchase investigation report by Arthur Anderson, 1988 (Box 11)
  - Reports on Germany (English and German), 1987-1989 (Box 11)
- Clients, Accounts, 1981-1996 and undated; 2
  - Burger King, 1982-1983; 1
    - European marketing strategy, 1983 (Box 11)
    - Have it your way UK strategy and execution recommendation, 1983 (Box 11)
    - JWT action plan for Europe, 1982 (Box 11)
    - Sales analysis, West Germany and Berlin 1981-1983 (Box 11)
  - Cockburn's Port, 1993; 2
    - Creative brief, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Computerland, 1984; 3
    - Europe media plans and evaluations, 1984 (Box 11)
  - Crown Berger Europe, 1988; 4
    - Crown Paints--Reports on nighttime television, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Crown relaunch outdoor media plan for 1988 (Box 11)
    - Project Lancashire 1988 media plan (Box 11)
  - Crown Decorative Products, 1987-1988 and undated; 5
    - Client correspondence, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Crown Paints--Budget-Billings, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Crown Paints--Call reports, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Crown Paints--Client correspondence, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Crown Paints--Competitive advertisements (Courtauld's Coatings, International Ranch Paint, Dulux Color collections), undated; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Crown Paints--Competitive advertisements, undated (Box 49)
    - Crown Paints--Creative strategy, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Crown Paints--Discussion plan, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Crown Paints--Media, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Crown Paints--Media recommendations, 1987-1988; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Crown Paints--Memos, 1988 (Box 11)
    - Crown Paints--Outdoor media proposal for 1988 (Box 12)
    - Crown Paints--Printed material, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Crown Paints--Project Lancashire outdoor buying briefs, 1988; 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Crown Paints--Retail marketing plan, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Crown Paints--Status reports 1988 (Box 12)
    - Crown Paints--Television contractor negotiations, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Crown Paints--TV ad review, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Crown relaunch 1988 media plan revision 3 (Box 12)
    - Crown Solo--Creative brief TV, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Crown Solo--Media package, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Crown Solo--Memos, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Crown Solo--Pre-test summary charts, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Crown Solo--Project Lancashire launch proposal, undated (Box 12)
    - Crown Solo--Research, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Crown Solo--Technical information, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Crown Solo--TV copy, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Marketing proposal, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Media progress report, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Project Lancashire--Discussion plan for 1988 (Box 12)
    - Project Lancashire--Media plan, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Project Lancashire--Test market media recommendations for 1988 (Box 12)
    - Report on a paint brand monitor, 1988 (Box 12)
    - Verdict on DIY retailers, 1988 (Box 13)
  - Ford Motor Company, 1983-1985 and undated; 6
    - ESO (European sphere of operations) car line budget recommendations, 1984 (Box 13)
    - European Ford group, 1984-1985; 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Ford of Europe communication needs, undated (Box 13)
    - Ford of Europe monthly reporting procedures, local agencies, central group London, 1983 (Box 13)
  - ITV (Independent Television), 1986-1993 and undated; 7
    - Approximate cost proposals for the design and implementation of new corporate identity on and off screen (overhead transparencies), 1989 (Box 13)
    - Change and opportunity presentation to chairman's committee, 1991 (Box 13)
    - Corporate identity qualitative research presentation charts, prepared by MRB, 1990 (Box 13)
    - Corporate identity, a report on qualitative research prepared by the qualitative workshop, British MRB, 1990 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1993; 3 folders (Box 14)
    - How to prosper despite growing and continuous competitive pressure, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Image of ITV: a report of a quantitative survey of the image of TV channels in the UK, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Image research, 1993 (Box 14)
    - Marketing the next two years, scripts from presentation, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Posters, 1989 and undated (Box 49)
    - Presentations, 1993 and undated; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Presentation: 1991-1993: A period of change, a period of challenge (overhead transparencies), undated (Box 14)
    - Presentation to Chairman's Committee, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Presentation to Dick Emery, 1993 (Box 14)
    - Presentation slides from qualitative research debrief, undated (Box 14)
    - Promotional airtime, 1991 (Box 14)
    - UK's favorite channel, undated (Box 14)
  - ITVA (International Television Association), 1990-1992 and undated; 8
    - 1992 advertising proposal (Box 14)
    - Advertisers campaign, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Creative work recommendations, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Market background, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Positioning and pricing now and in the future, undated (Box 14)
  - Kellogg, 1983-1996; 9
    - 1983-1984 ECS marketing plan (Box 15)
    - Cereals research computer tabulations, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Children's eating habits in Europe (Jo Cathro and Moira Hilliam), 1994; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Confidential project report: The average cost of a serving of Kellogg's Corn Flakes, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Copy tools, 1995 (Box 15)
    - Expanding the teenage franchise: A qualitative research study for Kellogg's Coco Pops and Frosties, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Promotions, 1993 (Box 15)
    - Rice business review, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Special K weekend copy, 1994 (Box 15)
    - UK interactive television test status report, 1996 (Box 15)
    - Variety 1996 creative development (Box 15)
    - Variety copy development, 1995 (Box 15)
  - Kellogg--Corn Flakes, 1981-1995 and undated; 10
    - Advertising development 1994-1995, 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Business objectives and strategies, 1994 (Box 15)
    - Comparisons of out of breakfast consumption 1989-1993 (Box 16)
    - Creating another role for KCF in people's lives: an integrated communications package, undated (Box 16)
    - Developing KCF long term communications strategy--Making the familiar unforgettable, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Directions for creative development of simple theme strategy, 1994 (Box 16)
    - Discussion on advertising development 1994-1995 (Box 16)
    - Kid theme, 1994 (Box 16)
    - Market modeling, brand dynamics, 1993 (Box 16)
    - Q4 equity and volume building ideas, 1995 (Box 16)
    - Recommendation on advertising development, presentation to Tim Mobsby, 1994 (Box 16)
    - Reprise of 1995 advertising development strategy, 1994 (Box 16)
    - Strategy presentation, 1994 (Box 16)
    - Summary findings of "value" research, 1993; 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Tabasco Sauce KCF opportunity, undated (Box 16)
    - Theme/value and kid advertising, undated (Box 16)
    - Value: there's more than one way to skin a cat, 1994 (Box 16)
    - What we know about breakfast, 1981 (Box 16)
    - Who is our consumer? a review of RI (Research International) consumption study, 1994 (Box 17)
  - Kellogg--Frosties, 1993-1996 and undated; 11
    - 1995 plan review (Box 17)
    - Action plans (presentation overhead slides), 1995 (Box 17)
    - Adult directed copy, copy strategy evaluations and recommendations, undated (Box 17)
    - Advertising development report, 1995 (Box 17)
    - Advertising idea research stage 2, 1995 (Box 17)
    - All roads lead to fun adult copy development research -- by McDonnell Spence, 1995 (Box 17)
    - Brand differentiation project proposal for research programme, 1996 (Box 17)
    - Brand differentiation project qualitative research debrief, 1996 (Box 17)
    - Connecting with young at heart adults, 1996 (Box 17)
    - Food improvement brief, 1995 (Box 17)
    - Frisbee and "Snowboarding" adaptations, 1995 (Box 17)
    - Gladiator promo (TV), 1994 (Box 17)
    - Hook, Eye of the Tiger, Tiger in You, impact and communications tests, 1994 (Box 17)
    - Inner child impact and communications test (Millward Brown), 1996 (Box 17)
    - Interactive TV trial videotron pilot results, 1996 (Box 17)
    - Managing the consumer interface through 1996 and beyond, 1995 (Box 17)
    - Presentation--Adult directed copy, 1994; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Presentation--Developing the poster campaign, 1996 (Box 18)
    - Presentation--Millward brown international, 1996 (Box 18)
    - Presentation--Theme copy for older kids, 1996 (Box 18)
    - Project "Sparkle" Frosties CDC research management report by McDonnell Spence, 1993 (Box 18)
    - Stage 1 media briefing, 1996 (Box 18)
    - Stage 1 planning for 1997, 1996 (Box 18)
    - Still young at heart, 1996 (Box 18)
    - Strategy presentation, 1996 (Box 18)
    - Theme campaign development, 1994 (Box 18)
    - Videotron correspondence and media clips, 1996; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Videotron interactive advertisers' forum, 1996 (Box 18)
    - Winning volume among the under 20s, 1994 (Box 18)
  - Kodak, 1982; 12
    - P-189 communications strategy for Europe, 1982 (Box 19)
  - Kraft, 1983; 13
    - Europe 1983 annual meeting official programme (Box 19)
    - International Account Directors' conference, 1983 (Box 19)
    - Mr. Gorla presentation, 1983 (Box 19)
  - Nestle, 1982-1985 and undated; 14
    - Advertising and sales promotion service NESTEC, 1983 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 19)
    - JWT summary of presentation to be given on september 29, 1982 (Box 19)
    - JWT worldwide factbook, 1982 (Box 19)
    - Nestle and JWT, undated (Box 19)
  - Pepsi, 1983 and undated; 15
    - Middle East presentation JWT, 1983 (Box 20)
    - Scandinavia and Iceland presentation, undated (Box 20)
  - Philips, 1982-1987; 16
    - Business review, 1982 (Box 20)
    - Meeting Amsterdam april 3, 1987; 3 folders (Box 20)
  - Schick, 1988; 17
    - European regional campaign project, 1988 (Box 20)
  - Unilever, 1983-1988 and undated; 18
    - Account worldwide billings and profits, 1983 (Box 20)
    - Client retention reports, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 20)
    - General correspondence, 1983-1984; 4 folders (Box 20)
    - General correspondence, 1983-1984; 4 folders (Box 21)
    - International Coordination group, London information bulletin, 1984 (Box 21)
    - International market summaries, 1983 (Box 21)
    - International market summaries, JWT brands, 1984 (Box 21)
    - JWT Supervisors' worldwide conference, London, 1983 (Box 21)
    - Lux toilet soap advertising review, 1984 (Box 21)
    - Persil automatic campaign, 1987-1988 (Box 21)
    - Persil automatic--Project Edward, 1987-1988 (Box 21)
    - Persil/Hotpoint cooperative, 1988 (Box 21)
    - Persil "Labels" campaign, 1987-1988 (Box 21)
    - Persil liquid--Project Nautilus correspondence and miscellaneous, 1988 (Box 22)
    - Persil liquid--Project Nautilus pre-production, 1988 (Box 22)
    - Persil liquid--Project Nautilus television copy, 1988 (Box 22)
    - Persil regular marketing plans, 1988 (Box 22)
    - Presentation--Detergents coordination, undated (Box 22)
    - Presentation--Personal products coordination, undated (Box 22)
    - Remuneration, 1983 (Box 22)
    - Trends in total advertising expenditure in 28 countries 1970-1982, 1983 (Box 22)
- Correspondence and Related Materials, 1975-1990 and undated; 3
  - Amsterdam, 1981-1986; 4 folders (Box 22)
  - Amsterdam--Business review meeting, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Amsterdam--Financial, 1984 (Box 22)
  - Amsterdam--New business plan, 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - Amsterdam--Profit plan meeting, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Athens, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Belgium advertising expenditures with the macroeconomic context, 1990 (Box 23)
  - Brussels, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Brussels--Financial, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Copenhagen, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Copenhagen--Financial, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Council of American survey research organizations, financial/compensation survey, 1984 (Box 23)
  - Cronin memos to all managers, 1983-1985 (Box 23)
  - Cronin notes on European Media Directors' conference, 1982 (Box 23)
  - Cronin presentation notes Santander, 1985 (Box 23)
  - Cronin speeches correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 23)
  - Cronin trip to Spain (English and Spanish), 1985 (Box 23)
  - Cyprus, 1981-1982 (Box 24)
  - David Campbell-Harris, 1985-1986; 3 folders (Box 24)
  - Deltakos, 1982-1984; 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Denis Lanigan, 1982-1986; 6 folders (Box 24)
  - Denis Lanigan, 1982-1986; 3 folders (Box 25)
  - Dan Robertson, 1982-1986; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Dan Robertson--Regional managers study, 1984 (Box 25)
  - Dubai, 1984-1985; 5 folders (Box 25)
  - Dubai, 1985-1987 (Box 26)
  - Dubai--An introduction to Thompson Advertising Middle East Limited Dubai, 1985 (Box 26)
  - Dubai--Cronin visit, 1985 (Box 26)
  - Dubai--Financial, 1985-1987 (Box 26)
  - Dubai--Financial 1985 year end financial report (Box 26)
  - Dubai--Gulf News, 1985 (Box 26)
  - Dubai--Meeting with TEKI, 1985 (Box 26)
  - Dubai--Tihami/TEKI (Tihami Eclair Kazan International), undated (Box 26)
  - EAAA--Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 26)
  - EAAA--Munare meeting, 1983 (Box 26)
  - EPCOT, 1984 (Box 26)
  - EPCOT--Cronin notes, 1984 (Box 26)
  - EPCOT--Interviews, 1984 (Box 26)
  - EPCOT--JWT company chronology, 1984 (Box 26)
  - EPCOT--JWT song, 1984 (Box 26)
  - EPCOT--Planning, 1983-1984 (Box 26)
  - EPCOT--Presentation, 1984 (Box 26)
  - EPCOT--Presentation "What clients want", 1984 (Box 27)
  - EPCOT--Program agenda and handouts, 1984 (Box 27)
  - EROC meetings, 1984 (Box 27)
  - Eric Jameson consumer study group, 1975-1982 (Box 27)
  - Euro Advertising International, 1984 (Box 27)
  - Euro Advertising International--Advertising agencies in Paris, a study of venture possibilities, 1984 (Box 27)
  - Europe, 1983-1984; 3 folders (Box 27)
  - European Managers meetings (includes photographs), 1978-1986 (Box 27)
  - European Media Directors' conference, 1982-1983 (Box 28)
  - European Media Directors' conference--JWT media planning philosophy (English and German), 1982 (Box 28)
  - France 1989 plan, 1988 (Box 28)
  - Frank Small and Associates acquisition, 1982-1984 (Box 28)
  - Frankfurt, 1984 (Box 28)
  - Frankfurt--Financial, 1984 (Box 28)
  - General correspondence, 1985; 5 folders (Box 28)
  - General correspondence, 1981-1986; 3 folders (Box 29)
  - General correspondence, Advertising Age focus panel, 1985 (Box 29)
  - Germany rebuilding action plan, 1989 (Box 29)
  - Germany restructuring, 1988 (Box 29)
  - Glen Dell, 1985-1986 (Box 29)
  - Greens (copies of outgoing correspondence), 1984; 4 folders (Box 29)
  - Greens (copies of outgoing correspondence), 1984; 9 folders (Box 30)
  - Greens (copies of outgoing correspondence), 1984 (Box 31)
  - Hamburg--Direct mail samples, undated (Box 31)
  - Harry Clark, 1984-1986 (Box 31)
  - Harry Clark--JWT new business manual, 1985 (Box 31)
  - Industry competitors, 1984-1987 (Box 31)
  - Industry competitors--Competitor analysis, 1983 (Box 31)
  - Industry competitors--How to solve the advertising problems of the multinational marketer (BBDO international), undated (Box 31)
  - Industry competitors--The quest for fire--AAAA annual meeting speech, 1984 (Box 31)
  - Istanbul, 1985-1987; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Istanbul, 1985-1987; 2 folders (Box 32)